class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}
List<QuestionModel> greenhouse_technology = [


  QuestionModel(question: "1. What is the primary purpose of a greenhouse in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Weed control",
        "B. Pest management",
        "C. Crop protection and growth",
        "D. Soil fertility improvement"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Greenhouses are designed to provide an ideal environment for crop growth, protecting plants from external factors and promoting their development. Thus, the correct answer is C.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "2. Which of the following gases plays a significant role in the greenhouse effect within a greenhouse?",
      options: [
        "A. Oxygen",
        "B. Nitrogen",
        "C. Carbon dioxide",
        "D. Hydrogen"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Carbon dioxide (CO2) is a crucial component in the greenhouse effect, helping trap heat and maintain a warm environment for plant growth. Therefore, the correct answer is C.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "3. What is the purpose of shading in greenhouse technology?",
      options: [
        "A. Reducing temperature and light intensity",
        "B. Enhancing nutrient absorption",
        "C. Increasing humidity",
        "D. Controlling pests"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'Shading in greenhouse technology helps reduce temperature and light intensity, preventing excessive heat and light exposure that may harm plants. Hence, the correct answer is A.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "4. Which greenhouse covering material is known for its excellent light transmission and durability?",
      options: [
        "A. Polyethylene",
        "B. Fiberglass",
        "C. Shade cloth",
        "D. Polycarbonate"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: 'Polycarbonate is a durable and transparent material commonly used as a greenhouse covering, providing excellent light transmission. Thus, the correct answer is D.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "5. What is the function of a thermal screen in greenhouse technology?",
      options: [
        "A. Reducing heat loss during the night",
        "B. Enhancing photosynthesis",
        "C. Increasing ventilation",
        "D. Controlling humidity"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'A thermal screen in a greenhouse helps reduce heat loss during the night, maintaining optimal temperatures for plant growth. Therefore, the correct answer is A.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "6. Which environmental factor is most crucial for controlling in greenhouse cultivation?",
      options: [
        "A. Rainfall",
        "B. Temperature",
        "C. Wind speed",
        "D. Atmospheric pressure"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Temperature control is crucial in greenhouse cultivation as it directly impacts plant growth and development. Thus, the correct answer is B.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "7. What is the purpose of a drip irrigation system in greenhouse agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Providing mechanical support to plants",
        "B. Delivering water directly to the plant roots",
        "C. Controlling pests",
        "D. Enhancing air circulation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'A drip irrigation system delivers water directly to the plant roots, promoting efficient water use and minimizing water wastage. Therefore, the correct answer is B.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "8. Which of the following is a benefit of using hydroponics in greenhouse cultivation?",
      options: [
        "A. Reduced water usage",
        "B. Increased soil fertility",
        "C. Enhanced weed control",
        "D. Improved natural pollination"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'Hydroponics allows for reduced water usage as it delivers nutrient-rich water directly to the plants, minimizing water wastage. Thus, the correct answer is A.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "9. What is the purpose of integrating CO2 enrichment in greenhouse environments?",
      options: [
        "A. Pest control",
        "B. Disease prevention",
        "C. Improved photosynthesis",
        "D. Weed suppression"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'CO2 enrichment in a greenhouse enhances photosynthesis, promoting plant growth and productivity. Hence, the correct answer is C.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "10. Which greenhouse structure is designed with a rounded roof for efficient snow shedding?",
      options: [
        "A. Gothic arch greenhouse",
        "B. Quonset greenhouse",
        "C. Gable roof greenhouse",
        "D. Lean-to greenhouse"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'A Gothic arch greenhouse is characterized by a rounded roof, allowing for efficient shedding of snow and providing structural stability. Therefore, the correct answer is A.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "11. In greenhouse technology, what is the purpose of using an automated climate control system?",
      options: [
        "A. Enhancing soil fertility",
        "B. Regulating temperature, humidity, and ventilation",
        "C. Controlling pests and diseases",
        "D. Providing structural support"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'An automated climate control system in greenhouse technology regulates temperature, humidity, and ventilation, creating an optimal environment for plant growth. Thus, the correct answer is B.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "12. What role does a shade cloth play in greenhouse management?",
      options: [
        "A. Enhancing light intensity",
        "B. Reducing sunlight exposure",
        "C. Providing mechanical support to plants",
        "D. Controlling pests"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'A shade cloth in a greenhouse helps reduce sunlight exposure, preventing excessive heat and light that may harm plants. Therefore, the correct answer is B.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "13. Which greenhouse covering material is known for its insulation properties and energy efficiency?",
      options: [
        "A. Polyethylene",
        "B. Glass",
        "C. Polycarbonate",
        "D. Shade cloth"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Polycarbonate is known for its insulation properties and energy efficiency, making it a popular greenhouse covering material. Thus, the correct answer is C.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "14. What is the purpose of a cooling system in a greenhouse?",
      options: [
        "A. Increasing humidity",
        "B. Reducing temperature",
        "C. Enhancing nutrient absorption",
        "D. Controlling pests"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'A cooling system in a greenhouse helps reduce temperature, preventing overheating and creating a favorable environment for plant growth. Hence, the correct answer is B.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "15. Which greenhouse component is responsible for promoting air circulation and preventing stagnant air?",
      options: [
        "A. Thermal screen",
        "B. Cooling system",
        "C. Ventilation system",
        "D. Shade cloth"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'A ventilation system in a greenhouse promotes air circulation, preventing stagnant air and maintaining a healthy growing environment. Therefore, the correct answer is C.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "16. What is the primary advantage of using a retractable roof in greenhouse construction?",
      options: [
        "A. Enhanced structural stability",
        "B. Improved natural pollination",
        "C. Efficient temperature control",
        "D. Reduced water usage"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'A retractable roof in greenhouse construction allows for efficient temperature control, enabling growers to adjust ventilation and manage the internal environment. Thus, the correct answer is C.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "17. What is the purpose of a fogging system in greenhouse cultivation?",
      options: [
        "A. Controlling pests",
        "B. Enhancing light intensity",
        "C. Reducing temperature and increasing humidity",
        "D. Improving nutrient absorption"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'A fogging system in greenhouse cultivation helps reduce temperature and increase humidity, creating an optimal environment for plant growth. Therefore, the correct answer is C.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "18. Which greenhouse covering material is known for its cost-effectiveness and light diffusion properties?",
      options: [
        "A. Glass",
        "B. Shade cloth",
        "C. Polyethylene",
        "D. Polycarbonate"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Shade cloth is known for its cost-effectiveness and light diffusion properties, making it a suitable greenhouse covering material. Thus, the correct answer is B.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "19. What is the purpose of using a blackout system in greenhouse cultivation?",
      options: [
        "A. Promoting natural pollination",
        "B. Enhancing photosynthesis",
        "C. Controlling pests and diseases",
        "D. Regulating light exposure"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: 'A blackout system in greenhouse cultivation helps regulate light exposure, creating a controlled environment for specific crops that require distinct light cycles. Hence, the correct answer is D.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "20. In greenhouse technology, what is the significance of integrating a weather station?",
      options: [
        "A. Pest control",
        "B. Improved natural pollination",
        "C. Precise climate monitoring",
        "D. Weed suppression"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Integrating a weather station in greenhouse technology enables precise climate monitoring, allowing growers to make informed decisions based on real-time weather data. Therefore, the correct answer is C.'
  )

];